<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>England's triumph, or, A poem on the royal camp at Hounslow-Heath</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1686</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A38445</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing E3063</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R8937</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">13274429</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 13274429</idno>
            <idno type="VID">98705</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A38445)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 98705)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 453:14)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>England's triumph, or, A poem on the royal camp at Hounslow-Heath</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed and are to be sold by Randall Taylor ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1686.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>In verse.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>James --  II, --  King of England, 1633-1701.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  James II, 1685-1688 --  Sources.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  London --  17th century</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-05</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-05</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="poem">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:98705:1"/>
            <head>
               <hi>England's Triumph:</hi> OR, A POEM ON THE ROYAL CAMP At <hi>Hounſlow-Heath.</hi>
            </head>
            <lg>
               <l>HEre, here the Bleſſed <hi>Albion</hi>'s Glory ſee;</l>
               <l>Here, here the Bleſſed <hi>Albion</hi>'s Worthies be;</l>
               <lg>
                  <l>Here may you ſee God <hi>Mars</hi>'s Seat of Pride,</l>
                  <l>And the Unconquer'd <hi>JAMES</hi> in Triumph Ride,</l>
                  <l>Who all Great <hi>Europes</hi> Monarchs has Out-vy'd.</l>
               </lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>Jove</hi> ſeemeth pleas'd to be; yet ſeems to Wonder</l>
               <l>He ſhould ſo briskly immitate his Thunder!</l>
               <l>But hold! <hi>See</hi> how our Monarch gains Renown,</l>
               <l>When with His Mart'al Pomp Encircl'd Round;</l>
               <l>But if They cover all the Spac'ous Plain,</l>
               <l>And add ten thouſands more to fill the Train,</l>
               <lg>
                  <l>Yet Mighty <hi>JAMES,</hi> not half Your <hi>Army</hi>'s here,</l>
                  <l>Heavens Guard'an <hi>Angels</hi> i'th' <hi>Liſt</hi> appear,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>They</hi> lead the <hi>Van,</hi> and <hi>Yours</hi> bring up the <hi>Rear.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <l>'Tis true, Mortals we know Yours are, but when</l>
               <l>We them behold, we ſcarce can think 'em Men.</l>
               <l>In them Immortal ſparks of <hi>Heav'nly Fire</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Do glow: And their Heroick Souls aſpire</l>
               <l>At Nobler <hi>Acts</hi> than e're their <hi>Sires</hi> Achiev'd:</l>
               <l>Their <hi>Courage</hi> is far Greater than believ'd.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Thou now for <hi>State</hi> they are Encamp'd in Peace,</l>
               <l>They breath all Fire and Conqueſt, ne're to ceaſe.</l>
               <l>How wou'd the mutual Shouts of Joy Accord,</l>
               <l>To ſee Great <hi>JAMES</hi> unſheath His Conqu'ring Sword,</l>
               <l>To Quell ſome Mighty <hi>Foe,</hi> that all might ſee</l>
               <l>The <hi>Worlds</hi> Great <hi>Worthies</hi> Crown'd with Victory;</l>
               <l>While each that in the meaneſt Rank does ſtand,</l>
               <l>Is able in a moment to Command.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The <hi>Earth</hi> whereon they ſtand ſeems proud to grow;</l>
               <l>The <hi>Trees</hi> at ev'ry <hi>Word</hi> do Cringe and Bow;</l>
               <l>The <hi>Hills</hi> and <hi>Valleys</hi> all rejoyce and Sing,</l>
               <l>And ſeem to Echo forth, <hi>Long Live the KING;</hi>
               </l>
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:98705:2"/>
               <l> 
                  <hi>Thames</hi> views the Field, and paſſing by, doth ſay,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>I'le ſurely Wait upon</hi> You <hi>twice aday.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Neptune</hi> Himſelf and <hi>Thetis</hi> are afraid</l>
               <l>Great <hi>JAMES</hi> ſhould his Unconquer'd World Invade.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Droop, Grinning Envy, droop, no more diſgrace</l>
               <l>The Royal Line, nor fly in <hi>JAMES</hi>'s Face;</l>
               <l>Confounded be; and Horrour pierce thy <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>reaſt;</l>
               <l>In laſting Agitation take no Reſt;</l>
               <l>Nor let thy <hi>Bas'lisk</hi> Eyes the Sume're ſee,</l>
               <l>Till thou'aſt disbanded all Diſloyalty.</l>
               <l>Nay Weep more <hi>Tears</hi> than drops of <hi>Water</hi> be</l>
               <l>Within the Briny Sea, to think that He</l>
               <l>Whom thou haſt <hi>Curſt,</hi> and <hi>Croſt,</hi> and ſo much wrong'd,</l>
               <l>Now Soars above thy Reach, and Great, Deſies</l>
               <l>What ever thou canſt baſely Enterprize.</l>
               <l>O never, never more thy Prince provoke,</l>
               <l>But Grace from all the Pow'rs of <hi>Heav'n</hi> Invoke.</l>
               <l>See <hi>Lucifer</hi> i'th' deep Abyſs of <hi>Hell:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Be Warn'd by him, thou'lt never more Rebel.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>England</hi>'s Great King on Earth ſo Reigns in Peace,</l>
               <l>As ſhews us all our future Happineſs.</l>
               <l>But former <hi>Hero</hi>'s I perhaps offend,</l>
               <l>In ſtriving thus our <hi>Caeſar</hi> to Commend:</l>
               <l>For here's requir'd a Stren'ous <hi>Homer</hi>'s Quill,</l>
               <l>A <hi>Spencer</hi>'s Pen, and brave <hi>Apelles</hi> Skill;</l>
               <l>But ſhou'd all theſe attempt, and thouſands more,</l>
               <l>Their Verſe wou'd look but like to Gold in <hi>Oare:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For as the Sun above the Stars do ſhine,</l>
               <l>Drawing its Luſter from the Pow'rs <hi>Divine;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Ev'n ſo does He above all Mortals Sway:</l>
               <l>Heav'n with a <hi>Greater</hi> never Crown'd the <hi>Day.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Stay, ſtay, and to the <hi>CAMP</hi> return again,</l>
               <l>Once more to View that Great and Glor'ous Train.</l>
               <l>Where Thouſands more do daily hither come,</l>
               <l>To ſee the <hi>Terrour</hi> of all <hi>Chriſtendom.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But now, juſt now, came flying to my Ear,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Orders</hi> were come, that all muſt diſappear;</l>
               <l>The Horſe, I ſee, are all Decamp'd and gone,</l>
               <l>The <hi>Town</hi> cries out, <hi>O Lord, We're all <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ndone!</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Come, come, let each his <hi>Hand</hi> lay on his Sword,</l>
               <l>Ready to <hi>Draw,</hi> when <hi>JAMES</hi> ſhall give the <hi>Word.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Then, then deſpond not, but <hi>All</hi> Faithful be</l>
               <l>To Grac'ous <hi>Faith-defending</hi> Majeſty:</l>
               <l>By <hi>Victory</hi> gain Honour to our King,</l>
               <l>While Echo's to His Mighty Triumphs Ring.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="license">
            <p>This may be Printed,</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <date>Aug. 13. 1686.</date>
               </dateline> 
               <signed>R. P.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed, and are to be Sold by <hi>Randall Taylor</hi> near <hi>Stationers-Hall,</hi> MDCLXXXVI.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
